rsca.be 2019-05-02

# Privacy policy | Official website Royal Sporting Club Anderlecht

**Privacy Policy RSCA.be**  
 **Last updated:** 25/04/2018

This “Privacy Policy” defines the processing of your personal data by the  
responsible of processing: RSC Anderlecht, with corporate address Theo  
Verbeecklaan 2, 1070 Anderlecht and registered under VAT  
number BE0823.379.451 (hereafter: “RSCA”).

This privacy policy describes the essential information and procedures in which  
your personal data is being processed.

By supplying your personal data on the website, the RSCA mobile application and  
the e-mail subscription forms, you accept having read the Privacy Policy and you  
specifically agree on all of the articles, including the way of processing as managed  
by RSCA.

**Article 1 – General**

1.1. RSCA complies for the processing of the personal data to the “Law agreed  
on December 1992 to the protection of the personal privacy in regards to the  
processing of personal data”, as updated by the Law of 11 December 1998 and the  
anti-spam definitions in Book XII of the Economic Rights Law, handling the  
“rights of the electronic economy”.

1.2. RSCA commits itself in addition to comply to the European Regulation  
2016/679 from April 27, 2016, regarding the Protection of the Personal Data  
(General Data Protection Regulation – GDPR).

**Article 2 – Personal Data**

2.1. Personal data which is shared with RSCA can be divided in 4 categories:  
– Category 1, without registration: your ip address  
– Category 2 : when registering on newsletter: your e-mail address;  
– Category 3 : through cookies: tracking of usage website and mobile app;  
– Category 4 : personal data and invoice data for fanshop and ticketing;

2.2. RSCA gathers your Personal Data in different ways:  
● By using cookies;  
● When registering to the RSCA website (ticketing and fanshop), RSCA mobile  
app, newsletter, contact forms and usage of the website;

2.3. The website uses cookies which gather limited personal data. For more  
about the cookie usage, please refer to the cookie statement of rsca.be.

**Article 3 – Purposes of the data processing**

3.1. General purpose:

RSCA will use the collected personal data only for the following purposes:  
– Category 1 : the provision and improvement of this website and the  
inclusion of Personal Data in anonymous statistics, from which the identity of  
specific persons or companies can not be determined, based on the legitimate  
interests of RSCA to continuously improve its Website and services;  
– Category 2: sending you direct marketing, newsletters, with your explicit  
prior permission as a legal basis. This permission can always be withdrawn;  
– Category 3: improving the user experience with your explicit prior consent  
as a legal basis;  
– Category 4 : the delivery and invoicing of products or services you request,  
with the legal basis for providing a product or service that you have requested.  
You are not obliged to release all requested personal data, but understand that the  
provision of certain services becomes impossible when processing is refused.

3.2. Direct marketing:  
If you are already included in our mailing list for receiving marketing material in  
paper and / or electronic form, RSCA can use your data for sending marketing and  
other material with regard to the various services. In these mailing lists, we only  
manage personal data for which an explicit consent has been given through an  
opt-in method on our website. If you are currently not included yet, you can sign  
up for our mailing list during the registration or purchase process (ticketing and  
fanshop), also by giving your explicit consent.  
This permission can be withdrawn at any time, without justification and free of  
charge by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided for this purpose. This  
unsubscribe link is sent to every email sent from a direct marketing point of view.  
RSCA will not sell your Personal Data, nor rent it out or make it commercially  
available to third parties (including the commercial partners of RSCA), unless  
with your prior consent and acknowledgment of receipt by the third party.

**Article 4 – Duration of processing**

The personal data is stored and processed by us for a period that is necessary in  
function of the purposes of the processing and in function of the contractual  
relationship between RSCA and yourself.  
Accounts which appear to be inactive during 5 years (no login to the online profile,  
use of the app, opening of newsletters, purchasing of tickets, fanshop purchases)  
will be permanently removed from our systems.

**Article 5 – Your rights**

The following rights in respect of your own personal data can always be exercised  
on simple request.

5.1. Right of access and inspection:  
You have the right to receive free access to your personal data at any time. For this  
RSCA provides an online tool where you can always review your preferences and  
data.  
5.2. Right of improvement, deletion and limitation:  
You are free to disclose your personal information or not to RSCA. In addition,  
you always have the right to request that we correct, supplement or delete your  
personal data. RSCA undertakes to process every request within a maximum of 72  
hours.  
5.3. Right of resistance:  
You always have the right to object to the processing of your personal data for  
serious and legitimate reasons or for the purpose of direct marketing.  
5.4. Right of transferability:  
You have the right to obtain your personal data in a structured format and / or  
transfer it to other responsible persons.  
5.5. Right of withdrawal of consent:  
If processing is based on your prior consent, you naturally have the right to  
withdraw that consent.  
5.6. Exercising your rights:  
You can exercise your rights by contacting us for this purpose, either by e-mail, to  
[dpo@rscanderlecht.be](mailto:dpo@rscanderlecht.be), by post to Theo Verbeecklaan 2, 1070 Anderlecht. An  
additional identification can be requested for identification purposes. For other  
requests (collaborations / contestation of content / placed links) contact can be  
made via the contact page.  
5.7. Automatic decisions and profiling:  
During the processing of your personal data, RSCA will build up a profile in order  
to offer you tailor-made services. However, these services are never offered  
completely individually. Data are only supplemented and requested when this is  
necessary and are only accessible for internal services at RSCA, provided that  
sufficient access rights are available.  
5.8. Right to complain:  
You have the right to file a complaint with the Belgian Privacy Commission:  
Commission for the Protection of Privacy, Drukpersstraat 35, 1000 Brussels, Tel  
+32 (0) 2 274 48 00, e-mail: [commission@privacycommission.be](mailto:commission@privacycommission.be).  
Article 6 – Security and confidentiality  
6.1. We have developed security measures that are technical and organizational  
adapted to avoid the destruction, loss, forgery, modification, unauthorized access  
or notification by mistake to third parties of personal data collected as well as any  
other unauthorized processing of personal data. this information.  
6.2. In no event can RSCA be held liable for any direct or indirect damage  
resulting from incorrect or unlawful use by a third party of the personal data.  
6.3. You must comply with the safety regulations at all times. You are therefore  
solely responsible for the use made of the website of your computer, IP address  
and your identification data, as well as for the confidentiality thereof.

**Article 7 – Access by third parties**

7.1. In order to process your personal data, we grant access to your personal  
data to our employees.  
7.2. We guarantee a similar level of protection by making contractual  
obligations enforceable against these employees and appointees, which are similar  
to this Privacy Policy.  
7.3. Advertising impressions and clicks can be registered by RSCA and by  
advertising networks in which RSCA participates. The following networks are  
active for this:  
● Doubleclick (Google DFP)  
7.4. RSCA Fanshop  
The online fanshop of RSCA is operated by a third party ('Gemaco') which is  
connected to the central database. After registration of an RSCA ID and clicking  
on to the RSCA fanshop, limited data is transferred to the third party (name, first  
name, e-mail address). These data may only be used by the third party in the  
context of the fulfillment of the online orders and are in no case shared with  
external parties for other commercial purposes. The third party undertakes to use  
their own General Terms and Conditions to accurately deal with the data  
obtained, both in terms of management and removal upon termination of the  
account at RSCA.

**Article 8 – Links to other websites**

8.1. RSCA is not responsible for the content of websites linked from RSCA by  
the administrator or visitors. The visitor is aware that the privacy of other  
websites may differ from RSCA.

8.2. A link to a website can not be considered for an explicit approval of the  
content of this website and the correctness can not be permanently guaranteed.

**Article 9 – Cookies**

9.1. We refer to the cookie statement of this website regarding the use of  
cookies.
